goalzero.com 2019-04-26

# Goal Zero - Privacy Policy / Goal Zero

This Privacy notice discloses the privacy practices for ([http://www.goalzero.com](http://www.goalzero.com/)). This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this web site. It will notify you of the following:

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
  2. What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
  3. The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.

Entering the site constitutes your acceptance and agreement to the terms contained in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy, please do not enter the Site. 

**Information Collection, Use, and Sharing**

Goal Zero LLC (“Goal Zero”, “we”, “us”, or “our”) is committed to the privacy of our customers (“you” and “your”). The Goal Zero Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) applies to Personal Information that Goal Zero collects, whether online, in person, through our call centers or otherwise. We collect information from you when you place an order, register on the site, enter a contest or sweepstakes, respond to a survey or marketing communication, email surf the website, or participate in another site feature(s). We use this information in order to provide you with the best possible service and to meet our reasonable business needs.

When ordering or registering, we may ask you for your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other information. You may also, however, visit our site anonymously.

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enhance your experience and gather information about visitors and visits to our websites. Please refer to the "Do we use cookies?" section below for information about cookies and how we use them.

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone.

We will use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, order, or any other service required by us for you. Terms and Conditions may vary when entering a contest or giveaway. Please refer to the specific terms and conditions of each contest.

Unless you opt out, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy.

**How Do We Use Your Information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you place an order, register on the site, enter a contest or sweepstakes, respond to a survey or marketing communication, email, surf the website, or participate in other site feature(s) in the following ways:

  * To personalize your site experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To quickly process your transaction.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

If you have opted-in to receive our email newsletter, we may send you periodic emails. If you would no longer like to receive promotional emails from us, please opt out or unsubscribe by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any of our emails/newsletters. If you have not opted-in to receive email newsletters, you will not receive these emails.

**Orders**

We request information from you on our order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (name, billing address, shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fulfill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we'll use this information to contact you. You can also place orders over the telephone by contacting customer service.

**Sharing**

We use an outside shipping company to ship orders (Federal Express, UPS, etc.), and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes beyond filling your order.

**Security**

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the web address (or URL) of the web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

We may include links to third party sites on our websites. When you click on those third party links, you leave the Goal Zero website. This Policy does not apply to third party sites or any information that you provide on those sites.

**Applications** Some of our products have applications available for download to your mobile device (“Apps”). The download and use of our Apps will allow you convenient access to the great experiences that our products have to offer, including the ability to manage your product’s features, control your products, and receive in-App notifications (collectively, the “Apps Services”). If you access our Apps, then we may be able to collect information about you. We may also associate the information collected through your use of the Apps to your customer profile. We may record and store archives of this data on servers to provide these features as well as to protect our rights in connection with our App Services and you acknowledge and agree to our storage of this data.

**Surveys & Contests** We may also collect your name, contact information, age and/or date of birth if you decide to participate in a marketing initiative such as a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion. In some cases we may also ask you specific questions about your preferences or for feedback on our business, products, services and programs. We use this information to administer the promotion, including contacting and announcing winners (where applicable), to improve our business, products, services and programs, and for marketing initiatives depending on your marketing preferences.We may use this information to respond to your question and to improve our business, products, services and programs. Participation in these surveys and/or contests is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information. Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. By entering any of our contests, giveaways, or surveys, you will be subscribed to and receive our email communications. You may however, opt out of these email communications by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any of the emails you receive.

**Do We Use Cookies?**

Yes. When you visit our website your web browser sends us certain information depending on the web browser that you use and your security settings. We may use tracking pixels/web beacons, cookies and or other technologies to receive and store certain types of information. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser information, Internet Service Provider (ISP), operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. This information helps us customize your website experience and make our marketing messages more relevant. It also allows us to provide features such as storage of items in your cart between visits. This includes our content presented on other websites or mobile applications. In order to provide the best customer experience possible, we also use this information for reporting and analysis purposes, such as how you are shopping our website, performance of our marketing efforts, and your response to those marketing efforts. We may collect your name, contact information and comments or questions when you submit an inquiry or comment, complete a survey or otherwise provide us with feedback about our business. 

  * Goalzero.com Cookies   
We may use cookies for us to better understand our site visitors, and provide more relevant and personalized experiences on our website. We do not store any personally identifiable information. The help function of your browser should contain instructions to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time. If you set your computer to not receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services cannot be provided to you, and accordingly, you may not be able to take full advantage of all the site features.

  * Third Party Cookies   
We may also use third party services, such as Google and Adobe Analytics and Facebook, that also use cookies and similar technologies, to provide us with information on how you interact with the content on our websites. For example, the webpage content that you click on, the duration of your visit to our website, and what website you visited prior to ours. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business. These third-party companies may collect anonymous information when you visit the site and use that information to serve ads for our products or services or for products or services. These companies may use anonymous information (e.g., navigational, non-personally identifiable information, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, etc.) during your visits to the site in order to provide advertisements about our goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These parties may use a cookie or third party web beacon, or other technologies, to collect this information.

To opt-out of third party vendor's cookies on other websites, visit the Network Advertising Initiative website, click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices

**Consent** Goal Zero collects, uses and discloses your Personal Information as outlined in this Policy and with your consent, except where permitted or required otherwise by law. We may be required or permitted under statute or regulation to collect, use or disclose Personal Information without your consent, for example to comply with a court order, to collect a debt owed to us or if there is an imminent threat to an individual’s health, safety, or well-being.

Your consent may be express (for example, oral, written, or electronic) or your consent may be reasonably inferred or implied from something that you do (for example, use of our websites, implies consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as described in this Policy). In some instances, an authorized representative may consent on your behalf. In the case of minor children, a parent or legal guardian may consent to our collection, use and disclosure of a minor’s Personal Information.

You may withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restraints. However, your withdrawal of consent might affect your experience and Goal Zero’s ability to provide products or services to you, or quick and accurate service to you either on-line or through our service agents.

**How to Manage Your Marketing Preferences** If you no longer want Goal Zero to use your personal information for marketing purposes, including to send you promotional communications, you may contact us (see “Contact Us” section below) and ask to be removed from our mailing and/or contact lists. We may ask you for more information where required in order to identify you correctly.

You may also manage your email subscriptions by clicking on “Unsubscribe” to stop receiving future promotional communications from us, or by clicking on “Manage My Email Preferences” found at the bottom of any of our emails you receive in order to manage your email subscriptions.

Children Under 13: Goal Zero does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen, without prior consent of the child’s parent or legal guardian. Goal Zero’s websites and social media pages available online are not directed to users under the age of thirteen. If you believe that your child under the age of thirteen may have provided Goal Zero with Personal Information online please contact us at [chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com) and we will take appropriate action.

Goal Zero requires the consent of the child’s parent or guardian for a child under the age of 13 to open an account or create profile related to an App. Parents and guardians understand that the App may collect information about their child, such as usage data. Goal Zero collects this information for the limited purpose of providing the App Services. Goal Zero does not collect or use this information in order to market products or services to children, and Goal Zero will not sell this information. To disable your child’s account, request a copy of the information, or ask a question about the App and your child’s data, parents and guardians should contact Goal Zero’s Chief Privacy Officer at [chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com)

**Access and Correction** Request a Copy: To obtain access to, or a copy of, your Personal Information that we have on file for little or no cost contact [chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com) or send a written request to 675 West 14600 South, Bluffdale, UT 84065 Attention: Chief Privacy Officer. Access to this information may be denied if you are unable to verify that you are the subject of the request. Information may also not be provided when giving you access to the information would threaten someone’s life or security, reveal third-party Personal Information, breach confidentiality, violate attorney/solicitor-client privilege, disrupt a formal dispute resolution, or impede a law enforcement investigation.

**Accuracy** We endevor to ensure that your Personal Information is as accurate, complete, and as up to date as necessary for the purposes for which it will be used or shared. If you would like to request correction of your Personal Information that we have on file you may write to [chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com) or 675 West 14600 South, Bluffdale, UT 84065 Attention: Chief Privacy Officer. 

**How We Protect Your Information** We will generally keep your Personal Information on file for a reasonable period of time in order to meet our needs as described herein and as applicable, the needs of the parties to whom we disclose it. This file will be maintained on our servers or those of our service providers and will be accessible by our authorized employees, service providers and representatives. We maintain reasonable and systematic controls, schedules, and practices to retain and destroy Personal Information.

Internal Protections: Goal Zero protects Personal Information by security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. We have policies and practices to protect against loss, theft, unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, modification, or destruction. While we make efforts to protect your information we are not in a position to guarantee that your Personal Information will always be secure. There may be factors beyond Goal Zero’s control which may result in loss or theft, or unauthorized access, use or disclosure of your Personal Information. As a consequence, we disclaim any warranties or representation on non-disclosure of your Personal Information. We also employ a Chief Privacy Officer to be accountable for Goal Zero’s compliance with these policies and whom you may contact at the address below with any question, concern or complaint.

External Protections: To protect information disclosed to service providers, Goal Zero uses contractual or other means to provide a similar level of protection so that service providers treat the information confidentiality, implement appropriate security measures and only use and disclose the information for the purposes of providing the applicable services.

**Responsibility** Goal Zero’s Chief Privacy Officer is responsible and accountable for Goal Zero’s compliance with this Policy and will handle all inquiries and complaints.

Contact Us: If you have any questions, you may contact us at:

Mail: Goal Zero LLC 675 West 14600 South, Bluffdale, UT 84065 Attention: Chief Privacy Officer

Phone: 1-888-794-6250 (North American Toll-Free) 

Email: [chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@goalzero.com)

**Subject to Change** This Policy is subject to change, and may be supplemented or modified at any time. You should check this site regularly to stay up-to-date about changes to this Policy. If material changes are made, we will notify you by placing prominent notice on our website www.goalzero.com/privacy-policy.

California Customers: California Civil Code Section 1798.83 entitles California customers to request information concerning whether a business has disclosed Personal Information to any third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Under this law, California residents may request certain information regarding our disclosures in the prior calendar year, if any, of their personally identifiable information to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at the address listed above. You must include sufficient detail in your request, such as your first and last name, email and postal addresses. We will attempt to provide you with the requested information within thirty (30) days of receipt. We reserve our right not to respond to requests sent more than once in a calendar year, or requests submitted to an address other than the one set out in this policy. As stated in this Privacy Policy, we will not sell your Personal Information.

**If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately via telephone at 1-888-794-6250 or via email[administrator@goalzero.com](mailto:administrator@goalzero.com)**

Last update: February 1, 2018
